(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
いっせーのーで、君とだけ！
Ready, set, go! Only with you!
ハイタッチ☆メモリー
High Touch☆Memory
もう少し眠りたいけど
I want to sleep a little more, but...
...もったいないよ今日は
...it's too good to waste today!
楽しいことやりたいこと
Fun things, things I want to do...
Wake Up！ 始めようよ
...Wake up! Let's get started!
めくるめく季節君と
Dizzying seasons with you...
...次のステージへ
...on to the next stage!
声を合わせ扉開けて
Joining our voices, opening the door...
...駆け出せ迷わずに
...run out without hesitation!
転んでもカッコ悪くてもイイじゃない
Even if you fall, even if it's uncool, it's fine!
Stand Up！ イメージもっと
Stand up! Keep layering the image...
...重ねて行くその先で
...and beyond that!
いっせーのーで、君とだけ！
Ready, set, go! Only with you!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて
High five! Clap your hands...
...奏でるメロディーを
...to the melody we play!
合図に走り出せ
At the signal, start running...
...君とならこわくない
...with you, I'm not afraid!
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて
High five! Hand to hand...
...重ねるこのメモリーは
...these overlapping memories...
...明日へのエネルギー
...are energy for tomorrow!
さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Let's go further ahead...
...君となら HAPPY LUCKY LIFE！
...with you, it's a HAPPY LUCKY LIFE!
あの日見た夢の続き
The continuation of the dream I had that day...
...追いつくその日まで
...until the day I catch up!
涙なんて振り切るくらい
Shaking off the tears...
...もっとスピードアップ！
...speed up even more!
どんな未来になったとしても
No matter what the future holds...
...後悔しないよ
...I won't regret it!
自分自身選んだ道
On the path I chose myself...
...踏み出せ迷わずに
...step forward without hesitation!
落ち込んで進めなくなった時は
When I'm feeling down and can't move forward...
Wake Up！ 思い出す
...Wake up! I remember...
...夢見た頃の記憶を
...the memories of when I dreamed!
手と手 奏でる
Hand in hand, we play...
...煌めく夢は
...this sparkling dream...
...君とだけ！
...is only with you!
ハイタッチ
High five!
その度に
Each time,
繋がっていく心
Our hearts connect more and more
一人じゃないことを
That I'm not alone
気付かせてくれたよね
You made me realize that, didn't you?
ハイタッチ 手と手叩いて
High touch, hands clapping together
奏でるそのメロディが
That melody we play
世界に届くまで
Until it reaches the world
この夢は続いていく
This dream will continue on
君となら HAPPY LUCKY LIFE!
With you, it's a HAPPY LUCKY LIFE!
ちわーす！ このライブに来てくれたスバ友！
Chiwassu! Subatomo who came to this live!
今日はいっぱい楽しんでってなー！
Please enjoy yourselves to the fullest today!
まだまだ盛り上がっていくぞー！
We're gonna keep on getting pumped!
挫けて歩けない日は おんぶしてあげる君を
On days you're discouraged and can't walk,
I'll give you a piggyback ride
ほら見てそっちの方が 強く地面踏み込める
Look, that way you can step on the ground
even more strongly
巡り巡る日々を 辿り夢見たステージへ
Through the cycling days,
to the stage I dreamed of
届くそんな日を 見つめて
Gazing at the day it finally reaches
起こそう君とだけ
Let's make it happen, only with you
手と手を鳴らすたび 小さなビッグバン
Every time our hands make a sound,
a small big bang
無限のその力を 受け取って進め！
Receive that infinite power and move forward!
ハイタッチ 手叩いて 奏でるメロディーを
High touch, clap your hands, the melody we play
合図に走り出せ
Start running at the signal
Go! 君となら怖くない
Go! With you, I'm not afraid
ハイタッチ 手と手叩いて
High touch, hands clapping together
重なるそのメモリーは
Those overlapping memories
明日へのエネルギー
Are energy for tomorrow
さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Come on, let's go even further
君となら HAPPY LUCKY LIFE!
With you, it's a HAPPY LUCKY LIFE!
夜に浮かんでいた 海月のような月が爆ぜた
The moon, floating in the night like a jellyfish, exploded
バス停の背を覗けば あの夏の君が頭にいる
Peering behind the bus stop,
you from that summer are in my head
ただ君に晴れ
作詞・作曲：n-buna
Tada Kimi ni Hare
Lyrics & Composition: n-buna
鳥居 乾いた雲 夏の匂いが頬を撫でる
Torii gates, dry clouds,
the scent of summer brushes against my cheek
大人になるまで ほら、背伸びしたままで
Until I become an adult, look, I'm still standing on tiptoe
遊び疲れたら バス停の裏で空でも見よう
When we're tired of playing,
let's look at the sky behind the bus stop
時期に夏が暮れても きっときっと覚えてるから
Even if summer ends soon,
I'm sure, I'm sure I'll remember
追いつけないまま大人になって 君のポケットに夜が咲く
Becoming an adult without being able to catch up,
night blooms in your pocket
口に出せないなら僕は一人だ それでいいからもう諦めている
If I can't say it out loud, I'm alone.
That's fine, so I've already given up
夏日 乾いた雲 山桜、錆びた標識
Summer days, dry clouds,
wild cherry blossoms, a rusted sign
記憶の中はいつも 夏の匂いがする
Inside my memories, it always smells like summer
写真なんて紙切れだ 思い出なんてただのゴミだ
Photos are just scraps of paper.
Memories are just trash
それがわからないから 口を噤んだまま
Because I don't understand that,
I keep my mouth shut
絶えず君の憩（いこ）い、記憶に夏野の石一つ
Endlessly your rest,
a single stone of the summer fields in memory
俯いたまま大人になって 追いつけないただ君に晴れ
Becoming an adult with my head down,
I can't catch up, just clear skies for you
口に出せないまま坂を登った 僕らの影に夜が咲いていく
Climbing the hill without saying a word,
night blooms in our shadows
俯いたまま大人になった 君が思うまま手を叩け
I became an adult with my head down.
Clap your hands as you please
陽の落ちる坂道を登って 僕らの影は
Climbing the hill as the sun sets, our shadows are...
ああ、追いつけないまま
Ah, still unable to catch up...
大人になって
Growing up,
君のポケットに
in your pocket,
夜が咲く
the night blooms.
口に出せなくても
Even if we can't say it,
僕ら一つだ
we're one.
それでいいだろ もう
That's enough, right?
君の思い出を噛み締めている
I'm chewing on the memories of you...
だけ
...only.
みんな！お待たせー！
Everyone! Sorry to keep you waiting!
ちゅあ、スバルにきてあじなすばー！
Tshua, welcome to Subaru's, Ajinasuba!
ということで始まりました、大空スバル3周年記念ライブ！
So it has begun, Oozora Subaru's 3rd Anniversary Live!
お待たせしましたー！
Sorry for the wait!
ということでですね、みんな今日はもう、どんどん、どんどん盛り上がっていきたいと思うんですけども、
So, I want to get more and more excited with everyone today,
まあ早速もうちょっと時間もあれだから次の曲にね、行ってみようかなと思いたいんですけど！
but since time is a bit limited, I'd like to move on to the next song!
なんとここでみんなには、練習してもらうことがあります！
But wait, there's something I want everyone to practice first!
それではこの方と一緒に練習どうぞ！ビデオスタート！
Now, please practice with this person! Video, start!
きたー！
It's here!
こんにちは、カバー株式会社の谷郷元昭です。
Hello, I am Motoaki Tanigo from Cover Corp.
こんにちはー！
Hello!
今日は大空スバル3周年記念ライブにお越しいただきありがとうございます。
Thank you for coming to Oozora Subaru's 3rd Anniversary Live today.
イエーイ！
Yay!
これからは大空スバル アイドルタイムになりますので、みんなと一緒に掛け声の練習をしたいと思います。
From now on, it's Oozora Subaru's Idol Time, so I'd like to practice the chants with everyone.
アイドルタイム！アイドルタイム！
Idol time! Idol time!
皆様もペンライトやコメントで打ってください。
Everyone, please type in the penlights and comments.
はい！もっとね！
Yes! More, right!
好きになって！
Fall in love!
＼もっと！／
\ MORE! /
まだまだ足りないぞ！もう一回行きます！
Not enough yet! One more time!
えー？あー！
Eh? Ah!
好きになって！
Fall in love!
＼もっと！／
\ MORE! /
なんなのそのポーズ！www
What's with that pose! LOL
私を見て！
Look at me!
＼もっと！／
\ MORE! /
なんなのそのポーズ！www
What's with that pose! LOL
完璧ですよ！完璧だな！このまま続けて聴いてください。
Perfect! That's perfect! Please continue listening.
大空スバルで「ファンサ」、そして初オリジナル曲「太陽少女」です。
Oozora Subaru with 'Fansa', and her first original song 'Taiyou Shoujo'.
はい！
Yes!
ということでみんな、突然出てきてびっくりしたんじゃないのかな？
So, everyone, weren't you surprised by the sudden appearance?
スバルも結構ちょっと色んな汗かいちゃった。
Subaru also broke into quite a few different sweats.
ですけどね、本当にYAGOOありがとう！
But really, thank you YAGOO!
ちなみにYAGOOの言った通り、ここからは2曲続けてやりたいと思いますので、
By the way, as YAGOO said, I'd like to perform two songs in a row from here,
それスバルも気持ち落ち着いて…ふー。
so Subaru needs to calm down... phew.
それではやりたいと思います！2曲続けて聴いてください！
Then, here we go! Please listen to two songs in a row!
ファンサ、太陽少女！
'Fansa', 'Taiyou Shoujo'!
好きになって もっと
Fall in love more
私を見て もっと
Look at me more
恩返しは
Repaying you
愛のこもった投げキッスで
with a blown kiss full of love
気のせいじゃない
It's not your imagination,
目は合ってるよ
our eyes are meeting
ハート作って
Make a heart
恋しちゃってください！
and please fall in love!
やれること
I'll do
何でもします
whatever I can,
NG無しで
no NG,
体当たり挑戦
a full-on challenge
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
Anti-comments I found while ego-searching,
「ふざけんな」誰より分かってるし
'Don't mess around', I know better than anyone
でも大丈夫
But it's okay,
ここに立てばみんながいる
when I stand here, everyone is here
いくよ！
Here we go!
君になって もっと
Become yours more
私を見て もっと
look at me more
恩返しは
Repaying you
愛のこもった投げキッスで
with a blown kiss full of love
虜にする もっと
I'll captivate you more
夢を見せる もっと
show you more dreams
楽しんでって
Have fun,
愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
a special night full of love
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'll give you fan service!
お手紙も
Please write
書いてください！
letters too!
何度も読んで
I'll read them over and over
宝物にします
and treasure them
スキャンダル
Scandal
まだ早いけど
is still too early,
裏切りません！
but I won't betray you!
宣言しときます
I'll declare it now
嫉妬 嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment
「ふざけんな」実力で勝ってやる
'Don't mess around', I'll win with my ability
だから辞めない
So I won't stop,
負けず嫌い 私はいる
I'm a sore loser, I'm here
いくよ！
Here we go!
拳上げて もっと
Raise your fists more
汗をかいて もっと
sweat more
恩返しは
Repaying you
愛のこもったスバビームで
with a Suba-beam full of love
大歓声 もっと
Great cheers, more
まだまだね もっと
not yet, more
受け止めてね
Accept it,
愛のこもったわがままソング
a selfish song full of love
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'll give you fan service!
終わりが...
The end is...
ファンサ
Fansa
近づく寂しいね
It's getting close, isn't it sad?
楽しいのに泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like I'm going to cry.
次も 次も また会えるよね
Next time, and the time after that, we'll see each other again, right?
約束！
Promise!
今日スバルのライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to Subaru's live today!
最後まで楽しんでってくれよなー！
Make sure you have fun until the very end!
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Words filled with kindness,
心ない誰かの言葉さえも
And even heartless words from someone,
必要なんだ 必要なんだ 強く成ろう
Are necessary, they are necessary to become stronger.
好きに叫べ もっと
Shout as you like, more!
楽しんじゃえ もっと
Have fun, more!
忘れないで 特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, I hope this becomes a special day.
共に歌おう ずっと
Let's sing together, forever.
共に歩もう ずっと
Let's walk together, forever.
合言葉は
The password is...
とびきりの L-O-V-E
The very best L-O-V-E!
好きになって もっと
Fall in love with me more,
私を見て もっと
Look at me more,
恩返しは 愛のこもった投げキッスで
My way of returning the favor is a blown kiss full of love.
虜にする もっと
I'll make you mine more,
夢を見せる もっと
I'll show you dreams more,
楽しんでって 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Enjoy this special night full of love.
ファンサしちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna give you some fan service!
太陽少女
Taiyou Shoujo
ギラギラの太陽が ワクワクが待ちきれない
The blazing sun, I can't wait for the excitement.
あれもしたい これもしたい 熱砂サマータイム
I want to do this, I want to do that, hot sand summertime.
ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！
Hy! Hy! Hy! Hy!
青い空と 白い雲が 心のボルテージ上げて行く
The blue sky and white clouds raise my heart's voltage.
ラムネ色の Tシャツはね 今年一番のレコメンド
The Ramune-colored T-shirt is this year's top recommendation.
走り出した 海岸線 どこまでだって行けそうだね
Running along the coastline, it feels like we can go anywhere.
数えきれない 夏休みだね 君も一緒に行こう
Countless summer holidays, you come along too.
あっという間に 進んでく時計 短すぎじゃない？マイサマータイム
The clock moves so fast, isn't it too short? My summertime.
全部最高の メモリアルにしたい 追い風 みんな連れていけ
I want to make it all the best memorial, let the tailwind take everyone along.
素晴らしい太陽がサンサン せーのでジャンプ 弾ける汗
The wonderful sun is shining brightly, jump on three! Bursting sweat,
宝石みたいにキラキラ光った 眩しく輝け
Sparkling like jewels, shine brilliantly!
ギラギラの太陽が ドキドキがいっぱいです
The blazing sun, I'm full of heart-throbbing excitement.
あれもやろう これもやろう 熱砂サマータイム
Let's do this, let's do that, hot sand summertime.
涼しい風 寝転がって のびのびとお昼寝もGood
A cool breeze, lying down, a relaxing nap is also good.
夢の中は 何だってできちゃう キラキラ光るよスーパースター
In dreams, you can do anything, shining bright like a superstar.
流れ星を 見つけに行こう 夜更かしだってへっちゃらだよ
Let's go find a shooting star, staying up late is no problem at all.
願い事が 溢れそうな時は ミルキーウェイダイビング
When wishes seem to overflow, Milky Way diving.
ちょっとくらい ヘタだって平気 みんながくれるファイトがある
It's okay to be a little clumsy, I have the 'fight' everyone gives me.
どこまでだって 駆け抜けて行けるから いいよね 準備OK？
Because I can run through anywhere, it's good, right? Ready?
みんな盛り上がってるかー！？
Everyone, are you hyped up?!
まだまだ盛り上がっていくぞー！！
We're going to keep getting more and more hyped up!
一歩一歩が 全部全部が 届いてるから上を向いて
Every single step is reaching, so look up.
身体中に 息を吸い込んだなら 叫ぶよ みんな大好きー！！
If you've inhaled deeply into your body, I'll shout it: I love everyone!
毎日が記念日になれ 君の心 照らそう
May every day become an anniversary, let me light up your heart.
新しい勇気を纏う 驚かせちゃうよ
Clad in new courage, I'll surprise you.
空の彼方まで飛んでいこう せーのでジャンプ 弾ける汗
Let's fly to the end of the sky, jump on three! Bursting sweat,
宝石みたいにキラキラ光った 眩しく輝け
Sparkling like jewels, shine brilliantly!
SUMMER time!
はい！ということで、太陽少女そしてファンサと･･･
Alright! That was "Taiyou Shoujo" and "Fan Service"...
どうだった？可愛かった？着替えたとこびっくりしたっしょ！
How was it? Was it cute? I bet you were surprised by the outfit change!
ちょっとね、お着替えなんかもしちゃったりしてね、いい感じにしました。
I changed my outfit a bit to make it look nice.
どうだったでしょうか？
What did you think?
もうね、本当に！もう本当に！バックダンサーたち見た、みんな？
Seriously! Seriously! Everyone, did you see the backup dancers?
あのさ、アヒルのさ、もう頭がさ、すごさ、ぴかぴかしててさ、スバルなんか楽しくなっちゃったよぉ。ん！
The ducks, their heads were so shiny, it made Subaru so excited. Yeah!
ということでですね、ここからはね、なんとね、また２曲･･･
So, from here, amazingly, there are two more songs...
ちょっとお水飲んでいい？普通に。ごめんなさい！
Wait, can I drink some water? Normally. I'm sorry!
あ、お水こっちだ。
Oh, the water is over here.
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
はい！ということで･･･あ、すみません。
Alright! So... Oh, excuse me.
ということでですね、ちょっとね、あの、ここからまた２曲あるんですよ。
So, there are two more songs from here.
で、この２曲ね、何だと思う？
And what do you think these two songs are?
ちょっと何だと思う？みんなが好きな曲と･･･
What do you think? One is a song everyone loves...
１曲は新曲、歌ったことない曲です。
...and the other is a new song, one I've never sung before.
え、何だと思う？っていうところも楽しみにして聴いてください。
What could they be? Please look forward to finding out.
それじゃあね、このアイドル衣装来ながら、そろそろね、始めちゃおうかな。
Well then, wearing this idol outfit, I'll start soon.
今からもう中盤だからね。もう、もう中盤だけど、まだ疲れてないよな？
It's already the middle of the show. We're halfway through, but you're not tired yet, right?
盛り上がっていくぞ！よし！ということで、じゃあ、始めるか！
Let's get hyped! Alright! Well then, shall we start?
それではね、じゃあ、聴いてください。
Well then, please listen.
Sincerely.
知らない言葉を覚えていくたび
Every time I learn a word I didn't know
面影の中に手を伸ばすの
I reach out my hand within the traces
だけど一人ではわからない言葉も
But there are also words I can't understand alone
あるのかもしれない
Maybe they exist
さよならは苦くて
Goodbye is bitter
アイシテルは遠い匂いがした
"I love you" had a distant scent
例えようのないこの思いは
This feeling that cannot be described
とても怖くて だけどとても愛おしくて
Is so scary, but so dear
私なんで泣いてるんだろう
Why am I crying?
心になんて答えたらいい？
How should I answer my heart?
言葉はいつでも語るでもなくて
Words are not always meant to be spoken
そこにあるばかり 募るばかり
They're just there, just growing
私はあなたに会いたくなる
I start wanting to see you
きれいな言葉を覚えていくたび
Every time I learn a beautiful word
自分のことが嫌になりそう
I feel like I'm going to start hating myself
だけど背を向けちゃいけないこともあるのかもしれない
But there might be things I must not turn my back on
悲しみは冷たく
Sadness is cold
ありがとうはぬくもりに色づく
Thank you is colored with warmth
形のないもの 触れるたびに
Every time I touch something formless
あなたの声が胸の奥で響いているの
Your voice is echoing deep in my chest
書きかけてはやめた
I started writing and then stopped
あて先のない手紙は風に揺れる
The letter without an addressee sways in the wind
届かない人の街まで
...to the town of unreachable people.
始まりの終わりを伝えるために
To convey the end of the beginning.
生きること　やめないこと
To live, to not give up.
あなたに今日　誇れるように
So that I can be proud of myself to you today.
私なんてと　抱いてるんだろう
I wonder if I'm embracing the words "someone like me".
誇りなんて　答えられたらいい
What should I answer as "pride"?
言葉はいつでも　語るでもなくて
Words are not always for speaking.
そこにあるばかり　募るばかり
They're just there, just growing.
私はあなたに　会いたくなるよ
I'll want to see you.
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
いいの？吸っちゃっていいの？
Is it okay? Can I suck?
「もう無理もう無理」なんて　悪い子だね
Saying "I can't take it anymore, I can't take it anymore". You're a bad kid.
(笑)
(laughs)
最低最高　ずっと行き来してる
Lowest, highest, going back and forth.
甘くなる不安の果実
The sweetening fruit of anxiety.
誰かと居れば　それはたられば
If I'm with someone, that's just a "what if".
強がってたって　気持ちにゃ逆らえない
Even if I act tough, I can't go against my feelings.
離れていても　感じてるエモ
Even if we're apart, I feel the "emo".
繋がってたしかめたら　死ねるかも
If I confirm our connection, I might die.
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
いいの？吸っちゃっていいの？
Is it okay? Can I suck?
「もう無理もう無理」なんて　悪い子だね
Saying "I can't take it anymore, I can't take it anymore". You're a bad kid.
試したいな　いっぱいで吐きたいな
I want to try. I want to be full and spit it out.
まだ絶対いけるよ
I can still go, absolutely.
屈んじゃって待って
Stooping down and waiting,
絡まっちゃって　これヤバい
getting tangled up. This is bad.
肝心なとこ忘れたら　はじめまして
If I forget the crucial part, then nice to meet you.
愛情ください　まだ絶対いけるよ
Give me love. I can still go, absolutely.
あたしヴァンパイア　まずはこっちおいで
I'm a vampire. First, come over here.
内緒の思い　洗いざらい　吐き出したなら　正にお盛ん
If I spit out all my secret thoughts, it's truly intense.
割り切れないけど　余りじゃない　そっと朝まで　通せんぼ
It's not divisible but it's not a remainder. Quietly blocking the way until morning.
繰り返すやだ　わがままはタダ
I don't want to repeat. Selfishness is free.
止まないもしも　叶えたいけど
Even if the "what ifs" don't stop, I want them to come true.
君の全てを喰らうまで　いいじゃん
Until I devour everything of yours, isn't it fine?
楽しんじゃん　気持ちいいじゃん
Enjoy it, feels good, isn't it?
溺れるまでが癖になるね
Getting addicted until I drown.
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
いいの？吸っちゃっていいの？
Is it okay? Can I suck?
「もう無理もう無理」なんて　悪い子だね
Saying "I can't take it anymore, I can't take it anymore". You're a bad kid.
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
いいの？吸っちゃっていいの？
Is it okay? Can I suck?
「もう無理もう無理」なんて　悪い子だね
Saying "I can't take it anymore, I can't take it anymore". You're a bad kid.
ほら絶対降参させてよ
Look, absolutely make me surrender.
屈んじゃって待って
Stooping down and waiting,
絡まっちゃって　何回目
getting tangled up. How many times now?
愛情ください　まだ絶対いけるよ
Give me love. I can still go, absolutely.
あたしヴァンパイア　まずはこっちおいで
I'm a vampire. First, come over here.
はーい！というわけで、Sincerelyとヴァンパイア、聴いていただきました！
Hi! And so, you've listened to "Sincerely" and "Vampire"!
どうでしたか？かっこよかった？かっこよかった？
How was it? Was it cool? Was it cool?
ふうー！ちょっとね、結構振り（付け）が激しい...
Whew! It was a bit... the choreography was quite intense...
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you very much!
あ、一曲目でしたー！
Ah, that was the first song!
もうちょっとね、バタバタしたんですけどね、
It was a bit hectic,
まあカッコよく決まってたらいいなと思います！
but I hope it looked cool!
はい！ということで、
Alright! So,
でもね、えーっと、なんだっけ？
but, um... what was it?
あ、そうそうそう！ここからは、
Oh, right right right! From here on,
今まではスバル一人だったんだけど、
I've been alone until now, but...
なんとここからはメンバーが会いに来てくれるとか！
guess what! From here, members will be coming to see me!
じゃじゃじゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
メンバーが会いに来てくれたりすると思います。
I think some members will be coming by.
でもね、まだ誰が来るかはお楽しみなんですよ。
But who's coming is still a surprise!
まだ言えないんです。
I can't say yet.
どんなメンバーがここにやってくるのか、
As for what kind of members will show up here,
みんなは楽しみにしながら待っててください！
please look forward to it and wait for them!
はい！
Yes!
で、スバルはちょっとここで一回お着替えね、
And I'm going to go change now.
もうちょっと衣装に戻すお着替えをしてこようと思うので、
I'm going to change back into my other outfit,
みんなちょっと待っててください。
so please wait a moment.
待っててね。
Wait for me.
はい、じゃあスバル行ってくるからちょっと待ってて。
Okay, I'm off now, so just wait a bit.
お水も飲んじゃうから。
I'm gonna drink some water too.
ふー。お水を飲むぜ。
Phew. Drinking some water.
はー、めっちゃ喉鳴った。やべー。
Hah, my throat really made a sound. Oops.
よし！
Alright!
おらー！
Oraaa!
どう、このイカしたサングラス！
How about these cool sunglasses!
どう、このイカしたサングラス。いいでしょ。
How about these cool sunglasses? Pretty good, right?
なんとね、今からパーティーの気分でね、
I want to get us pumped up now
盛り上げていきたいと思いまーす！
with a party vibe!
じゃあ、そろそろ行っちゃおうかな。
Well, shall we get started?
それでは、誰が来るかお楽しみ。
Now, look forward to seeing who comes.
聴いてください、you&me！
Please listen to "you&me"!
you&me
作詞：羽月美久  作曲：小松一也
Lyrics: Miku Hadzuki  Composition: Kazuya Komatsu
瞳にキラキラワンダーランド
Sparkling wonderland in your eyes
夜空にキスしたバタフライ
A butterfly that kissed the night sky
おいでエンジェル 一緒に眩い
Come here, Angel, let's shine together
恋のデコレーション
A decoration of love
まるでストロベリー甘い
Just like a sweet strawberry
ビームの上に
On top of the beam
おいで とっておきのハッピー飾ろう
Come, let's decorate with a special kind of happy
いくつもの鍵で 君と扉を開ける
Opening the door with you using many keys
星のジュエリー 降り注ぐシャイニングマイドリーム
Star jewelry raining down, shining my dream
テトテメトメ ヒトリトヒトリ
Hand in hand, eye to eye, person to person
出会って「ふたり」になる You & Me
Meeting and becoming "two", You & Me
君がいるってそれだけで ハーモニー始まるでしょう
Just because you're here, a harmony will surely begin
夜が朝に 季節が花に
Night turns to morning, seasons turn to flowers
出会って未来になる You & Me
Meeting and becoming the future, You & Me
愛よりもっと ラブな笑顔で
With a smile more filled with love than love itself
終わんない HAPPY DANCE
A non-ending HAPPY DANCE
テトテメトメ 魔法のトキメキ
Hand in hand, eye to eye, a magical heart-throb
魔法もゲンキも絶対減らない Ah
Magic and energy will absolutely never fade, Ah
見つめたその目はヤバい きらめく星を散りばめちゃうんだ
Those eyes you stared with are dangerous, they'll scatter sparkling stars
虹色シューズで空中旅行 (One Two!)
Space travel in rainbow shoes (One Two!)
いたずら小悪魔ベビーフェイス (Oh Yeah!)
A mischievous little devil with a baby face (Oh Yeah!)
なんだってできるご機謙な気分 (One Two!)
I can do anything, I'm in a great mood (One Two!)
ドキドキしたいわ (Come On!)
I want to feel my heart race (Come On!)
指先にキラリ ネイルのブルームで
Sparkling at my fingertips, with a nail bloom
パラダイス 空のカケラを閉じ込めたいな
Paradise, I want to lock away a fragment of the sky
見つめ合うたびに おもちゃ箱をにけだす
Every time we look at each other, they escape from the toy box
恋のメロディ 奏でてグローリーマイドリーム
Melody of love, playing my glory dream
テトテメトメ ヒトリトヒトリ
Hand in hand, eye to eye, person to person
出会って「ふたり」になる You & Me
Meeting and becoming "two", You & Me
君がいるってそれだけで サニーデイ特別なの
Just because you're here, it's a special sunny day
音が歌に 心が声に
Sounds turn into songs, hearts turn into voices
出会って言葉になる You & Me
Meeting and becoming words, You & Me
ハイよりもっと フルなボリュームで
More than "high", with full volume
伝えたい BABY LOVE
I want to tell you, BABY LOVE
(1, 2, 3, 4, Now Ready to)
もっともっと 熱いステージへ
To a hotter and hotter stage
夢はホログラムだらけ
The dream is full of holograms
ラストから今まで 愛のファンファーレ鳴らせ
From the end until now, let the fanfare of love ring out
どんなはちゃめちゃな夢でも こうやって真剣に信じ続けていれば
No matter how crazy the dream, if you keep believing in it seriously like this...
リアルになるいつかは
it will become real one day.
どんな場面だって pinky pump
No matter the scene, pinky pump
ヒトツトヒトツ　ヒトリトヒトリ
One and one, person and person
出会って　フタリになる you & me
Meeting and becoming two, you & me
ヒトリじゃないって　それだけで good morning
Just not being alone makes it a good morning
始まりでしょ　ヨルガアサニ
It's the beginning, night into morning
キセツガハナニ
Seasons into flowers
出会って　ミライになる you & me
Meeting and becoming the future, you & me
愛よりもっと　ラフな笑顔で
With a smile more casual than love
終わんない happy dance
An unending happy dance
It's for you and me, let's go!
Go Go Go Go! It's for you and me!
Go Go Go Go! On the funky beat!
ハヤサデラミノ
With the speed of...
It's for me, for you, and me
だから Check it out! Check it out! Yo!
So Check it out! Check it out! Yo!
はい！ということで、スバル、ルナ、チョコ先生、
Alright! So, we've just seen Subaru, Luna, Choco-sensei,
ぼたんちゃんのYou & Me見てもらいましたー！
and Botan-chan perform "You & Me"!
どうでしたか？ルナ、大丈夫？生きとるか？
How was it? Luna, you okay? Are you still alive?
大丈夫、大丈夫。
I'm okay, I'm okay.
死んどるやないか。はい、ということで、力の限りを尽くしたこれ、
You're clearly dead. Anyway, you gave it everything you had,
ルナ。ちゃんとやってたもんね。
Luna. You did a great job.
偉い！
Good girl!
ねえ、なんでぼたんちゃん、肩もんでたの途中で。
Hey, Botan-chan, why were you massaging her shoulders halfway through?
いや、ちょっと2番も頑張ってもらおうと思って。
Well, I wanted her to hang in there for the second verse too.
あ、頑張って。頑張ってねって。チョコ先生のこれ勢い強すぎて
Ah, like "Keep it up, keep it up." Choco-sensei, your momentum was so strong,
めちゃくちゃ怖かったんだけど、スバル。
Subaru was actually pretty scared.
いやだってね、掛け声はもう、やんなきゃなと思って。
Well, I felt like I just had to do the shouts properly.
やったけど気合いが。チョコ先生はもう全力でやってたよ。確かに。
You did, but the spirit... Choco-sensei was definitely going all out.
一人だけ昇龍拳みたいになってた。すげえの、もう。
She was like doing a Shoryuken all by herself. It was amazing.
ねえ。ということで皆さんありがとうございましたー！
Right. Anyway, thank you very much, everyone!
せっかくなので、写真でもね、撮りたいなーと思うんですけど。
Since we're all here, I'd like to take some photos.
おー！いいのー、写真撮りたい、撮りたい。
Oh! That sounds good, I want to take photos, I want to take photos.
じゃあルナのとこ集合！
Alright, everyone gather around Luna!
じゃあちょっとね、メガネを... 家族写真か！
Now, let's put on the glasses... It looks like a family photo!
じゃあ撮るよー。このね、メガネもね、わためからサングラス借りました。
Okay, taking the picture. These glasses, I borrowed the sunglasses from Watame.
イエーイ、ありがとうございます。パリピサングラス。はい、チーズ！
Yay, thank you. Party-people sunglasses. Say cheese!
ルナ、どこ見てんの？
Luna, where are you looking?
みんなどこ見てんの？
Where is everyone looking?
確かに。このカメラを見なきゃいけない。このカメラ。こっちな。そうだよ。
True. We have to look at this camera. This one. This way. That's right.
はい、チーズ！
Say cheese!
はい、ありがとうございまーす。
Alright, thank you very much.
え、あとさ、ちょっとさ、チョコ先生とぼたんちゃんが、あの、足長いから、
Oh, and also, Choco-sensei and Botan-chan have such long legs,
うん、こっち来て。
so come over here.
何？何？スバルじゃできないことしてあげるわよ。
What? What is it? We'll do something Subaru can't do.
なんやそれ！足、ルナと変わんないから、スバル。
What's that supposed to mean! My legs aren't that different from Luna's.
ルナのが長いだろ、お前ら。じゃあ足出して、こうやって、前に。
Wait, Luna's are longer? You guys... Okay, stick your legs out like this, in front.
足長いけど。
Our legs are long, but...
足なげー、二人！チョコ先生とぼたんちゃん！
Your legs are so long, you two! Choco-sensei and Botan-chan!
腰の位置高すぎだろ！ちょっとこれ、やばいよ、ルナ。やばい。
Your waists are so high! This is crazy, Luna. Crazy.
なんかスバルたちやばい。
Subaru and Luna look kinda bad next to them.
え、じゃあさ、二人ともさ、ここでさ、うん、こうやってさ、
Well, how about you two stand here, and like,
スバルたちよくゾンビしてるから、戦隊モノっぽいの撮りたくて、ここで、こうやって二人で。
Subaru and Luna often play the zombies, so I want to take a Super Sentai-style photo with you two doing this.
おー、OK。
Oh, OK.
スッ... おおー！新着。で、ルナとスバルで、ここで、背中合わせで仁王立ち。
Woah! That's new. And Luna and Subaru will stand back-to-back here.
チョコ先生セクシーだな。やばい、マジでやばい。
Choco-sensei is so sexy. This is crazy, seriously crazy.
カメラ上、上にお願いします、カメラ。あ、これ、これですよ。
Camera up, please tilt the camera up. Ah, this is the one.
あ、隠れてる？こう？上から目線だったら大丈夫。
Oh, am I hidden? Like this? It's fine if it's from a high angle.
あ、見下ろし視線。あ、いいじゃん、いいじゃん。
Ah, a looking-down perspective. Oh, this is good, this is good.
なんか椅子がある。椅子があるけど。ありがとうございます。
There's a chair there. A chair is in the way, but... thank you.
はい、これね。ちょっとサングラスも取りたいな。
Right, this one. I also want to take some without the sunglasses.
さ、取る？おいきたー！シュンシュン。
Okay, taking them off? Here we go! Swish, swish.
おい、いいじゃん。シャキーン。どうあがいても家族写真になっちゃうな。
Oh, this is nice. Sparkle! No matter what we do, it ends up looking like a family photo.
ありがとうございましたー。
Thank you very much.
はい、ということでね、いいよ。なんでこんな家族っぽくなっちゃうんだろうねー。
Alright then, that's good. I wonder why we look so much like a family.
はい、ということでね、今日は本当に来てくれてありがとうございました！
Well, anyway, thank you all so much for coming today!
あ、スバルもダンスの振り付けとかありがとう。
Ah, and thank you too, Subaru, for the dance choreography and everything.
あ、そうそう！ちょっとね、もう、どの、どれが一番いいかなーってね、
Oh, right! I was thinking about which parts would be best,
もう朝まで考えたんでね、みんなもう一回見直してくださいね、この後。
and stayed up until morning thinking about it, so please watch it again later, everyone.
はい、じゃあ最後に、なんかスバル3周年なのね。
Alright, so finally, it's Subaru's 3rd anniversary.
だから、3周年おめでとうって言って、バイバイしたい。
So, I want to say "Happy 3rd Anniversary" and then say goodbye.
しょうがねえなー。しょうがねえなー。
I guess we have no choice. I guess we have no choice.
なんやそれ！今なんか、あれ、スバル変なこと言った？
What's with that reaction! Did I just say something weird?
なんでこんなシーンとなっちゃうんだってなっちゃうんで。
I was wondering why it suddenly went so quiet.
じゃあ最後、みんなおめでとうって言ってくれる？
So, for the end, will everyone say congratulations?
いいともー！いいよー。ありがとう。
Sure thing! Okay! Thank you.
今日の温度差半端ない...
Today's temperature difference is crazy...
せーの！
Ready, set...
温度誰取ってるんだろう
I wonder who's taking the temperature?
じゃあ、ちょっと、せーので3周年おめでとうって言ってもらっていい？
Alright, can you guys say "Happy 3rd anniversary" on "Ready, set"?
せーの！
Ready, set...
3周年おめでとうー！
Happy 3rd anniversary!
おめでとうー！ということで、みんな、ちょこるなーたんでした！
Congratulations! So, everyone, that was Choco-Luna-Tan!
みんなまたねー！
See you later, everyone!
ありがとうねー！おめでとうー！
Thank you! Congratulations!
またねー！
See you!
黒子、黒子...
Black-clad stagehand, stagehand...
なかよし。か。
Friend... ly.
はい！ということでですね！じゃあ、ここからはね、
Alright! So! From here on,
またどんどんジャンジャンバリバリ踊っていきたいと思うんですけども！
I'm going to keep dancing more and more!
まあその前に、一旦お着替えタイムいきたいと思いますので、みんなちょっと待っててください。
But before that, I'm going to take a break for an outfit change, so please wait a moment.
そいじゃあみんな待っててね！行ってきまーす！
So everyone, wait for me, okay? I'm off!
よいしょ。よいしょ。お水飲んで。
Heave-ho. Heave-ho. Drinking water...
はぁ！
Haa!
よし！
Alright!
行くぞ！
Here I go!
おっちゃー！戻ってきたよー！
Ocha! I'm back!
ということで！まあここからはもう後半戦差し掛かってるので！
So! We're already heading into the second half of the show!
でも！後半戦だからって！まだまだいけるよな！盛り上がっていきたいと思います！
But! Just because it's the second half, doesn't mean we can't keep going! Let's get fired up!
それでは聴いてください、夜もすがら君想ふ。
Now, please listen. "Yomosugara Kimi Omou".
夜もすがら君想ふ
作詞・作曲: TOKOTOKO
Yomosugara Kimi Omou
Lyrics/Composition: TOKOTOKO
僕が生まれる前よりも ずっと昔から続くように
Just like it's been continuing since long before I was born
そういつも傷つけ合ってまた愛し合うのさ
We always hurt each other like that, and then love each other again
結婚や仕事のトークに またちょっと疲れてたとしても
Even if we're a bit tired of talking about marriage and work again
そう僕の独り言なんかじゃあない 分かってるのさ
It's not like I'm just talking to myself. I know that.
Hey! 明けない夜はないと
Hey! They say there's no night that doesn't end
夜明け前がただ暗いと
And that it's just darkest before the dawn
この先待つ明日が そんなに輝くもんかな
I wonder if the tomorrow waiting ahead will really shine that much
今 I love you で始まる僕らを もっと照らしてくれよ
Now, shine more light on us as we begin with "I love you"
変わらない愛や希望の類いもまだ 信じてみたいのさ
I still want to believe in things like unchanging love and hope
ほら I miss you で諦めムードでも 吹き飛ばしてくれよ
Look, even if there's a mood of giving up with "I miss you", blow it away
時代柄暗い話題が待ち受けても 愛を謳う
Even if dark topics await us in this day and age, I'll sing of love
僕が取るに足らないことで いつも悩んだりしてるのは
The reason I'm always worrying about trivial things is...
言っちゃえばアダムとイブからもう 決まってたのさ
To put it simply, it's been decided since Adam and Eve
Hey! なんとなく恋に落ちて
Hey! Falling in love for no particular reason
いつの間にか本気だって
And before I knew it, I was serious
張り裂けそうな胸の奥を 打ち明けなくちゃかな
I guess I have to reveal what's deep inside my bursting heart
行くぞ！
Let's go!
今 I love you で始まる僕らを もっと満たしてくれよ
Now, fill us up more as we begin with "I love you"
イメージ通りに運ばぬ僕らでも まだ信じてみたいのさ
Even if things don't go as we imagined, I still want to believe
ほら I miss you で賞味期限がある Oh yes! 急かしてくれよ
Look, with "I miss you", there's an expiration date. Oh yes! Hurry me up
時代柄暗い未来が待ち受けても 愛を謳う
Even if a dark future awaits us in this day and age, I'll sing of love
あの日夜明け前まで 君の声が聴きたい Oh yeah!
I want to hear your voice until before the dawn that day. Oh yeah!
ミオンちゃまへ！
インスタやらん？ｗ なんだかんだ素直なミオンちゃま好き！！
これからもよろしくね！！！
To Mion-chama!
Wanna do Insta? lol I like the surprisingly honest Mion-chama!!
Let's keep being friends!!!
あくあへ！
SAO次いつ見るの！！ 2期いつもまとめてくれてありがとー！！
あくあが同期でよかった！
To Aqua!
When are we watching SAO next!! Thanks for always summarizing season 2!!
I'm glad Aqua is my genmate!
ちょこ先へ！
またおとまりしよー！！！ ちょこ先は行動力の鬼すぎで尊敬してる！！
またアウトレット行こう！ｗ
To Choco-sen!
Let's have another sleepover!!! Choco-sen is a beast when it comes to taking action, I respect you!!
Let's go to the outlet again! lol
あやめどのへ！
あやめどのご飯食べたい！！ あとミオさんにも会いたいぞ！
あやめも3年だ！ 4年目もよろしくな！！
To Ayame-dono!
I want to eat Ayame-dono's cooking!! Also I want to see Mio-san!
It's been 3 years for Ayame too! Let's do our best in our 4th year!!
今 I love you で始まる僕らを もっと照らしてくれよ
Now, shine more light on us as we begin with "I love you"
変わらない愛や希望の類いもまだ 信じてみたいのさ
I still want to believe in things like unchanging love and hope
ほら I miss you で諦めムードでも 吹き飛ばしてくれよ
Look, even if there's a mood of giving up with "I miss you", blow it away
時代柄暗い話題が待ち受けても 愛を謳う
Even if dark topics await us in this day and age, I'll sing of love
ずっと昔から続くように
As if it's been continuing since long ago,
互いに傷つけ合ってまた愛し合うのさ
we hurt each other and then love each other again.
はー！ということで！
Phew! So!
うわー！やべー！
Whoa! This is intense!
おー！このダンスに...
Wow, this dance is...
ちょっと待って！お水！お水お水お水！
Wait a second! Water! Water, water, water!
はい！ということでね、夜もすがら君想う、いかがでしたか？
Alright! So, how was "Yomosugara Kimi Omou"?
もう超難いんだよ、これ。
This one is super hard!
カッコよく踊れてたでしょうか？
Did I look cool while dancing?
ということで、それではここで...
Alright, so at this point...
ここでですね、なんと、3周年記念グッズの紹介をしたいと思います！
Right here, I'd like to introduce my 3rd-anniversary goods!
はい！ということで、3周年記念グッズですね。
Yes! Here are the 3rd-anniversary goods.
まず、フルセットがホワイトとブラックがあります。
First, the Full Sets come in White and Black.
これは何がホワイトとブラックかというと、Tシャツの色が違うだけです。安心してください。
The only difference is the T-shirt color, so don't worry.
特典はですね、大空スバル箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード！
The bonus is an Oozora Subaru foil-stamped replica message postcard!
今回ちょっとね、直筆じゃないんですけどね、カードがついてきます。
It's not handwritten this time, but it comes with a card.
しぐれうい先生の描き下ろしカードです！
It's a newly drawn card by Shigure Ui-sensei!
はい、そして内容はですね...
Yes, and the contents are...
ラバーマット！ついに出るぞ、ラバーマット！
A rubber mat! It's finally here, a rubber mat!
ということでね、しぐれうい先生の描き下ろしのラバーマット！
A rubber mat with a new illustration by Shigure Ui-sensei!
なんと！めスバルとスバルが二人いる、大空スバル盛り合わせセット！
It's an Oozora Subaru assortment set featuring both "Mesubaru" and Subaru!
そして、『ぷれあです』のですね...
And, about "Pleiades"...
今回のライブタイトル『ぷれあです』の、なんとCDが出ます！
A CD for this live's title track, "Pleiades", is coming out!
何だってー！大変だ！これはね、初のCDで、
What?! No way! This is my first CD, and
あの、色々入ってるんですよ、曲が。
it's packed with various songs.
ちょっとまだ言えないんだけど、あの、曲がいっぱい入ってて、
I can't say everything yet, but it has a lot of songs,
カバーソングもね、『奏』と、あと『ファンサ』が入る予定で、
and cover songs like "Kanade" and "Fansa" are planned to be included,
あとオリジナルボイスもこの中についてます。CDよかったら買ってください。
plus original voice tracks. Please buy the CD if you like!
えー、そして！ついにですね、Tシャツを出すことになりました！おめでとう！
And finally! I'm releasing a T-shirt! Congratulations!
みんながね、ワンポイントが着やすいって言ったからね、ワンポイントにしました！
Everyone said a simple design would be easy to wear, so I went with that!
これがホワイトとブラックがあって、セットもあるけどバラ売りもあるという感じです。
It comes in white and black, and it's available both in the set and individually.
はい、そして...
Yes, and...
なんと！新曲が出るぞ！
What! A new song is coming out!
この新曲はですね、今回のライブタイトルの『ぷれあです』という新曲が出ます！
The title track for this live, "Pleiades", is coming out as a new song!
10月7日木曜日、24時配信開始です。
Streaming starts on Thursday, October 7th, at midnight.
CDの中にもですね、『ぷれあです』入ってて、あとインストも入ってます。
The CD also includes "Pleiades" and its instrumental version.
作詞はですね、ミトさん。そして作曲はですね、滝澤俊輔さんがですね、してくれました！
Lyrics are by Mito-san, and the composition is by Shunsuke Takizawa-san!
マジで最強の曲なので、みんなぜひ聞いてください！はい！
It's a truly amazing song, so please listen to it! Yes!
ということでね、ちょっと、ちょっとね、足早に駆けちゃって、
So, I rushed through that a little bit,
汗がヤバいんだけど！
and I'm sweating like crazy!
はい、ということでですね、ここからですね、
Alright, so from here,
まだみんな聞きたい曲あるんじゃないのー？
don't you guys have more songs you want to hear?
あ、ヤゴーと同じポーズしちゃった。聞きたい曲あるんじゃないのー？
Oh, I did the same pose as Yagoo. Don't you have more songs you want to hear?
なんとですね、今から『ぷれあです』新曲をですね、披露したいと思います！
Actually, I'm going to perform my new song "Pleiades" right now!
はい！もうラストなのでね。せっかくたからじゃあ真ん中のですね、
Yes! It's the final part, so
ステージで踊って歌っちゃおうかな！それじゃあ真ん中のステージにレッツゴー！
I think I'll sing and dance on the center stage! Then, let's go!
これね、長いんだよ！
This runway is long!
もうすごい！みんな、見えてるよー！うわー！走っていくよー！
It's amazing! I can see everyone! Whoo! I'm running!
ドンドン、ドンドン... 来たー！
Thump, thump... I've arrived!
はー！ということで、皆さんね、今からね、新曲歌って最後盛り上がって終わりたいと思います！
Phew! So, everyone, I'll sing my new song now and end this with a bang!
新曲だけじゃないよ、まだ曲は何曲かあるからね！
It's not just the new song, there are a few more!
はい！ということでね、最後まで盛り上がっていきましょう！
Yes! So, let's keep the energy up until the very end!
それでは聴いてください、大空スバルオリジナルソング、ぷれあです！
Now, please listen: Oozora Subaru's original song, "Pleiades"!
ちょこっとヤンチャで
A little bit mischievous,
ニコっと元気な
With a cheerful smile,
キラッとスマイル アイドル
A sparkling smile idol.
毎日もっと楽しくしたい
I want to make every day more fun,
貪欲ウィズアドベンチャー
A greedy adventure.
ヒラヒラスカートも
Even this fluttering skirt,
ちゃんと着こなせてるんだよ
I can pull it off perfectly.
だからもっともっと気になってもいいよ
So it's okay to be more and more interested,
一緒に
Together,
大空に飛び出そう！
Let's fly out into the great sky!
Starlight どんな輝きの中も強いキラメキ
Starlight, a strong sparkle amidst any brilliance.
キミに届いているかな？
Is it reaching you?
1ミリでも伝われ Fight oh!
Even if it's just 1mm, let it be conveyed! Fight oh!
チャージしてなんて 全力アクセル
Charge up! Full throttle,
頑張るキミへ
To you who are doing your best.
一番乗りのスマイルを送る スバルちゃんねる
Sending the very first smile, Subaru Channel.
Everyday 悩んで みんなで！
Everyday, worrying, together with everyone!
ブルーな気持ちに ズバっと駆けつけ
Rushing in to save those blue feelings,
お助けしちゃうヒーロー
The hero who comes to your aid.
弱いハートじゃいられないから
I can't have a weak heart,
つよつよで行きましょう
So let's go with strength!
ハラハラ水引いて
Nervous, as the water recedes,
どきどきのときめきたい
I want that heart-pounding excitement.
いつでもおいでよ 一年中パラダイス
Come anytime, it's a paradise all year round,
ドッカンと
With a bang!
曇り空吹き飛ばそ あがれ！
Blow away the cloudy skies, rise up!
スターマイン どんな暗闇の中も眩しく照らす
Star mine, brightly illuminating even the deepest darkness.
キミに見つけてもらえた
Since you found me,
それだけでもう運命なんだ
That alone is destiny.
もっとずっと道は続いてく
The road continues much further,
夢に向かって
Towards our dreams.
一緒に来てくれるかな？
Will you come with me?
その手と手走れ
Let's run, hand in hand.
連れて行くよ みんなで！
I'll take you there, with everyone!
前座作 恥ずかしいけれど
An opening act, it's embarrassing but,
伝えたい想い
These feelings I want to convey,
今なら言える
I can say them now.
キミのエールが力になるよ
Your cheers give me strength,
いつも元気をわけてくれて
Thank you for always sharing your energy.
頑張っていけるんだ 笑って過ごせるんだ
I can keep doing my best, I can spend my days laughing,
本当に
Truly.
ありがとうの気持ちを歌え！
Sing out your feelings of gratitude!
Starlight どんな輝きの中も強いキラメキ
Starlight, a strong sparkle amidst any brilliance.
キミに届いているかな？
Is it reaching you?
1ミリでも伝われ Fight oh!
Even if it's just 1mm, let it be conveyed! Fight oh!
もっとずっと道は続いてく
The road continues much further,
夢に向かって
Towards our dreams.
一緒に来てくれるかな？
Will you come with me?
その手と手走れ
Let's run, hand in hand.
連れて行くよ みんなで！
I'll take you there, with everyone!
キミと駆ける スバル
Running with you, Subaru.
想いの冒険を
Without forgetting
忘れずに全部言えるかな
The adventure of my feelings, can I say it all?
キミから聞きたいよ
I want to hear from you,
何回目の僕に出会った
Which 'me' did you meet?
僕は変わりました
I have changed,
新しいキミに出会うために
In order to meet the new you.
久しぶりだねって 言えたんなら
If I could say 'It's been a while',
ここで泣こうか
Should we cry here?
好きとかって 嫌いとかって
Whether it's liking or hating,
何度だって愛を歌うキミが
You who sing of love over and over again,
恋しくて 嘘じゃない 本当だよ
I miss you, it's not a lie, it's the truth.
また出会おう
Let's meet again
僕らを祝って
Celebrate us
位置に戻って
And back to our positions
何回だって
No matter how many times
間違ってこれたよ
I could make mistakes
消えない後悔と
Unfading regret and
冷めない愛情が
Cooling affection
恋をリブートする
Will reboot love
ほら I を嫌って
Look, hating 'I'
また II に戻って
Returning to 'II' again
III になって
Becoming 'III'
愛を抱いていこう
Let's hold onto love
言いたい感情は
The feelings I want to express
伝えたい正解は
The answer I want to convey
たった一つだけ　ありがとう
Is just one thing: thank you
想いの冒険は
The adventure of my thoughts
これからもちゃんと続いていく
Will properly continue from now on
3と9に乗って
Riding on 3 and 9
言葉とか飛び越えちゃって
Jumping over words and such
君も変わりました
You've changed too
新しい誰かに会うために
To meet someone new
大人になりました
I've become an adult
それだけでいいと思えた
I could think that's enough
好きとかって　嫌いとかって
Things like liking or hating
何度だって　愛を歌う君が
You who sings of love over and over
恋しくて　嘘じゃない　本当だよ
I miss you, it's not a lie, it's the truth
また出会おう
Let's meet again
恋をして馬鹿
A fool in love
愛にして馬鹿
A fool in affection
馬鹿でいよう　この先も
Let's stay fools from now on
ずっとこのまま　馬鹿
Just like this, fools
何回だって
No matter how many times
間違ってこれたよ
I could make mistakes
消えない後悔と
Unfading regret and
冷めない愛情が
Cooling affection
恋をリブートする
Will reboot love
ほら I を嫌って
Look, hating 'I'
また II に戻って
Returning to 'II' again
III になって
Becoming 'III'
愛を抱いていこう
Let's hold onto love
言いたい感情は
The feelings I want to express
伝えたい正解は
The answer I want to convey
たった一つだけ　ありがとう
Is just one thing: thank you
うおー！
Whoa!
スバルの3周年、みんなと一緒にいられて、
Subaru's 3rd anniversary, being with everyone,
本当に、ありがとう！
really, thank you!
これからもずっと、よろしくお願いします！
Please continue to support me forever!
今これまでに　ありがとう
Thank you for everything up until now
いつまでも君と　こうして歌った
Sang like this with you forever
愛を数えられぬように
So that love can't be counted
3周年ありがとう！これからもずっと君と一緒に！
Thank you for the 3rd anniversary! Always with you from now on!